A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Appointments Office, Series 2 FA353
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller gubernatorial records, Appointments Office, Series 2
1958-1970
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ronan, William J. (William John)
Morrow, Hugh
Boyd, Joseph H.
New York (State). Governor (1959-1973: Rockefeller)
Cannon, James M.
Whitman, Ann
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
New York (State). Dept. of Civil Service
New York (State). State Commission for Human Rights
FA353
4 Box(es)
Arrangement note
The following 24 series are available for research. Missing numbers denote closed series.
Series 2 - Appointments Office Series 3 - Assembly and Senate Memos Series 4 - Joseph H. Boyd Files Series 7 - James Cannon Files Series 8 - Affirmative Action Files (N. Lee Cook) Series 10 - Counsel's Office Series 12 - New York State Committee to Reelect the President Series 13 - Jerry A. Danzig Files Series 14 - Executive Chamber Series 16 - 55th Street Series 17 - Issue Books Series 19 - Arthur Massolo Files Series 22 - New York Office Series 23 - Civil Service Resolutions (Charles H. Palmer) Series 24 - Political Files Series 25 - Press Office Series 27 - Public Relations Series 28 - Departmental Reports Series 29 - William J. Ronan Files Series 33 - Speeches Series 34 - Diane Van Wie Files Series 35 - Ann C. Whitman, Gubernatorial Files Series 36 - Gene Wyckoff Files Series 38 - New York Republican State Fund Raising Reports
Biographical/Historical note
Nelson A. Rockefeller served as governor of New York from January 1, 1959, to December 18, 1973. He was the first person elected to four consecutive four-year terms as a state governor.
File Plan note
Former Classification: III 15 2
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for scholarly research, except where particular restrictions are noted.
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
Scope and Contents note
NOTE TO RESEARCHERS
This subseries contains a portion of the office files of several members of Nelson A. Rockefeller's staff, primarily the Appointments Office. They document official activities in the execution of their duties as members of Rockefeller's staff. The actions, decisions, and exchanges of information or points of view documented here occurred in the course of proposing and implementing policies for the Rockefeller administrations, political campaigns, and/or Rockefeller's personal activities. However, unless a document is specifically addressed to or from Nelson A. Rockefeller, or is referred to in a document addressed to him, it should not be assumed he saw the document or was aware of its existence or substance. Furthermore, researchers should bear in mind that staff files may contain documents or drafts addressed to Rockefeller that were never shown to him.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
This is an incomplete portion of Governor Rockefeller's Appointments Office correspondence, dating from 1958 to 1970. Only three boxes of alphabetical correspondence are represented, from C through L. There is no record or indication of what happened to the rest of the alphabetical run. The final box of the series is a box of miscellaneous subject files, dating from 1967 to 1970. Alphabetically arranged by topic, this portion of the series is also incomplete. The material contained withing these files may be duplicated within the official gubernatorial record, maintained on microfilm at both the New York State Archives and the Rockefeller Archive Center.
A function of the Appointments Office was to sift through the letters of application received for positions in the gubernatorial administrations. The series consists of correspondence to and from the individuals making application, as well as internal memoranda to and from other staff of the Appointments Office or to staff of the various state-level departments to which an applicant was referred.
Other Finding Aids note
Detailed finding aids for each series of this collection are available:
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Assembly and Senate Memos (FA354)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Joseph H. Boyd (FA355)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, James Cannon (FA356)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Affirmative Action (N. Lee Cook) (FA357)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Counsel's Office (FA358)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York State Committee to Reelect the President (FA359)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Jerry A. Danzig (FA360)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Executive Chamber (FA361)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, 55th Street (FA362)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Issue Books (FA363)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Arthur Massolo (FA364)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Hugh Morrow (FA242)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Office (FA365)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Civil Service Resolutions (Charles H. Palmer) (FA366)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Political Files (FA367)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Press Office (FA368)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Public Relations (FA369)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Departmental Reports (FA370)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, William J. Ronan (FA371)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Speeches (FA372)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Diane Van Wie (FA373)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Ann C. Whitman, Gubernatorial (FA374)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Gene Wyckoff (FA375)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Republican State Fund Raising Reports (FA376)
Presidential campaigns -- United States; Political science; Latin America; International relations -- United States; International relations; International economic relations; Political campaigns -- United States; New York (State); New York (N.Y.); Legislation -- New York (State); Arms control -- United States; Civil defense; Civil defense -- United States; Civil service; Human rights; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1970; Affirmative action programs -- New York (State); Arms control; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1962; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1958; Presidential candidates -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1966; Economics; Civil service -- New York (State); Government policy; Federal government -- United States; Vice-Presidents -- United States; Public relations; Public policy; United States; State governments -- United States; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- )
- Correspondence Files (Car-Caz), 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence Files (Car-Caz), 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence Files (Ce-Ch), 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence Files (Ce-Ch), 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence Files (Cl), 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence Files (Coa-Con), 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence Files (Coa-Con), 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence Files (Coo-Coz), 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence Files (Cr-Cz), 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence Files (Cr-Cz), 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence Files - Crouch, Paul A. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Scope and Contents note
  Letters of endorsement for Crouch to serve as Commissioner of Commerce.
- Correspondence Files - Crouch, Paul A. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence Files (Da) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence Files (Dea-Del) (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence Files (Dem-Dez) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence Files (Di) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence Files (Dm-Do) (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence Files (Dp-Dz) (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence Files (Dp-Dz) (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence Files (E) (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Correspondence Files (E) (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Correspondence Files (Fa-Fe) (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Correspondence Files (Fia-Fin) (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Correspondence Files (Fia-Fin) (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Correspondence Files (Fio-Fiz) (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Correspondence Files (Fl-Fo) (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Correspondence Files (Fra-Fre) (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Correspondence Files (Fri-Fuz) (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Correspondence Files (Ga) (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Correspondence Files (Ga) (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Correspondence Files (Ge-Gh) (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Correspondence Files (Gi) (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Correspondence Files (Gl) (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Correspondence Files (Go) (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Correspondence Files (Go) (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Correspondence Files (Gra-Gre) (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Correspondence Files (Gri) (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Correspondence Files (Gu) (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Correspondence Files (Hab-Hal) (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Correspondence Files (Ham-Hat) (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Correspondence Files (Hau-Haz) (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Correspondence Files (He) (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Correspondence Files (Hi) (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Correspondence Files (Ho) (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Correspondence Files (Hu-Hy) (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Correspondence Files (I) (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Correspondence Files - Inauguration, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  Requests to Governor Rockefeller for tickets to President Lyndon Johnson's inaugural ball.
- Correspondence Files - "Italian-American Herald" (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Correspondence Files (J) (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Correspondence Files (J) (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Correspondence Files (Ka) (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Correspondence Files (Ke) (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Correspondence Files (Kh-Ki) (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Correspondence Files (Kl-Kn) (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Correspondence Files (Ko) (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Correspondence Files (Kr-Ky) (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Correspondence Files (La) (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Correspondence Files (La) (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Miscellaneous Files - Abortion, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  Correspondence, memoranda on abortion in New York State, including statistical information and material on the Committee to Study Abortion Laws in New York State, reports, polling data on abortion, medical reports, statistical information, legal precedents.
- Miscellaneous Files - Abortion, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Miscellaneous Files - Abortion, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 61)
- Miscellaneous Files - Abortion, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 62)
- Miscellaneous Files - Abortion, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 63)
- Miscellaneous Files - Abortion, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 64)
- Miscellaneous Files - Abortion, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 65)
- Miscellaneous Files - Abortion, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 66)
- Miscellaneous Files - Abortion, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 67)
- Miscellaneous Files - Oaths of Office, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  Listings of individuals with addresses, title and salary grade, and department affiliation. Lists note oaths of office received between July 1968 and October 1969.
- Miscellaneous Files - Oaths of Office, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 69)
- Miscellaneous Files - Oaths of Office, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 70)
- Miscellaneous Files - Oaths of Office, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 71)
- Miscellaneous Files - Press Releases, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  Selection of press releases, primarily concerned with positions in the state government.
- Miscellaneous Files - 1969 Summer Employment (Box 4, Folder 73)
  Memoranda, correspondence, and records regarding youth employment in New York State.
- Miscellaneous Files - 1969 Summer Employment (Box 4, Folder 74)
- Miscellaneous Files - 1970 Summer Employment, Division of Parks (Box 4, Folder 75)
  Memoranda, correspondence, and records regarding youth employment in the New York State Department of Parks.
- Miscellaneous Files - 1970 Summer Employment, Social Services and Conservation (Box 4, Folder 76)
  Memoranda, correspondence, and records regarding employment in New York State summer schools and in the Department of Conservation.
- Miscellaneous Files - 1970 Summer Employment, Social Services and Conservation (Box 4, Folder 77)